I am here to sign a document betting
$10,000
this video is correct. In this car there
is no motor, no batteries, no energy
source besides the wind itself. And the
counterintuitive claim is that this car
[music] can maintain speeds faster than
the wind that's pushing it.
>> No one is perfect, uh but uh you have a
much lower error rate than most uh
people on YouTube.
>> Now, Professor Alex Kusenko wanted this
wager and all related discourse to be
public. In fact, he suggested we get a
celebrity to witness the signing. So, I
asked Neil deGrasse Tyson, Bill Nye, and
Sean Carroll to be our witnesses and
they graciously agreed. [music]
For the first video, I asked my friend
and YouTube maker Zyla Foxlinn to make a
model downwind cart.
Version one ended in failure, but Zyla
was undeterred coming back in a couple
days with version two. Unlike these
models, most of her projects actually
work. She is determined.
>> It's
>> I'm going to make the claim on camera. I
like I think it's going to work this
time.
Her fourth version of the cart worked
spectacularly and it was designed to be
replicated by anyone using just a 3D
printer and a simple list of materials.
Now, Professor Kusenko has now conceded
the bet and he transferred $10,000 to
me. So, I want to thank him for being a
man of honor and changing his mind in
light of the evidence I presented, which
is really not easy to do especially in a
public debate like this one.